<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.openownership.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.openownership.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-16T17:04:52+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/</id><title type="html">OpenOwnership</title><subtitle>Building an open register of global beneficial ownership in the public interest</subtitle><entry><title type="html">We’re hiring!</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/were-hiring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We're hiring!" /><published>2018-09-28T13:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T13:27:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/were-hiring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/were-hiring/">&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, the idea of public registers of beneficial ownership was a campaigner’s long-shot. Now, with governments across the world committed to collecting and publishing information on the people who really own companies, we are are making it a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backed by DFID, we are now poised to take our tools and support into the mainstream and deliver our first organizational strategy. This means growing our team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently hiring for the following roles, offering an opportunity to drive and shape work with the potential for real impact on anti-corruption and corporate transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for an all-rounder Software Engineer, with a solid backend background and some front-end experience. You will work with the Product Owner and developer/s to define software requirements and develop high-quality software that is aligned with user needs and project goals. You will be responsible for developing, testing, improving and maintaining the Register to help users retrieve data effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1UULjbrOf1HR509NuIJQP3MWAolJ98DBWntwDZx05JG0/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for full details on the role and how to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communications Associate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also looking for an experienced consultant to provide a range of communications support to OpenOwnership’s project team on a contract basis until at least 31st March 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1G53u30gb3YZYSubh7Bmik84MBMeveCgbILem-ZyZccM/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Please see our brief&lt;/a&gt; for more information on our requirements and the application process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ten years ago, the idea of public registers of beneficial ownership was a campaigner’s long-shot. Now, with governments across the world committed to collecting and publishing information on the people who really own companies, we are are making it a reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kyrgyzstan joins OpenOwnership’s pilot program</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/kyrgyzstan-joins-openownerships-pilot-program/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kyrgyzstan joins OpenOwnership’s pilot program" /><published>2018-09-13T10:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-13T10:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/kyrgyzstan-joins-openownerships-pilot-program</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/kyrgyzstan-joins-openownerships-pilot-program/">&lt;p&gt;We’re delighted to announce that Kyrgyzstan is the latest country to join OpenOwnership’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/the-openownership-pilot-program/&quot;&gt;pilot program&lt;/a&gt;. Through this program, OpenOwnership will support the government of Kyrgyzstan in collecting and publishing high quality, open access beneficial ownership data for applicants and holders of oil, gas and mining licenses. The resulting data will be automatically available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;OpenOwnership Register&lt;/a&gt;, and linked to other beneficial ownership data from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenOwnership has worked closely with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eiti.org/&quot;&gt;Extractives Industry Transparency Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (EITI) to develop this partnership with Kyrgyzstan. A successful pilot program will result in Kyrgyzstan implementing its commitment to EITI to have in place a publicly accessible register of the beneficial owners of companies holding mining licenses by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mining accounts for nearly 9% of Kyrgyzstan’s GDP, with gold the biggest contributor. The country was one of the first to commit to increasing transparency in this sector, signing up to the EITI in 2004. Since then, Kyrgyzstan has worked with EITI to make significant progress towards greater transparency, and in 2018 passed a new Subsoil Law that requires beneficial ownership information for applicants and mining license holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to EITI, there are only two other countries - UK and Ukraine - that disclose beneficial ownership through open and accessible registers. By participating in the OpenOwnership pilot program, Kyrgyzstan will become pioneers in providing EITI beneficial ownership as open data in a form that can be linked globally, based on OpenOwnership’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://openownership.org/news/coming-soon-a-beneficial-ownership-data-standard/&quot;&gt;data standard&lt;/a&gt;. Through this work, OpenOwnership will identify learnings that can apply across other EITI countries working to meet beneficial ownership commitments, and integrate these into our implementation guidance for governments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to our partners at the EITI International Secretariat and the Kyrgyzstan EITI Secretariat for their work so far towards making this partnership possible. We look forward to continuing our work with EITI and working with the Kyrgyzstan State Committee and technical implementers over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the OpenOwnership pilot program and the benefits to your country or organization, contact Louise at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:louise@openownership.org&quot;&gt;louise@openownership.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We’re delighted to announce that Kyrgyzstan is the latest country to join OpenOwnership’s pilot program. Through this program, OpenOwnership will support the government of Kyrgyzstan in collecting and publishing high quality, open access beneficial ownership data for applicants and holders of oil, gas and mining licenses. The resulting data will be automatically available on the OpenOwnership Register, and linked to other beneficial ownership data from around the world. OpenOwnership has worked closely with the Extractives Industry Transparency Initiative (EITI) to develop this partnership with Kyrgyzstan. A successful pilot program will result in Kyrgyzstan implementing its commitment to EITI to have in place a publicly accessible register of the beneficial owners of companies holding mining licenses by 2020. Mining accounts for nearly 9% of Kyrgyzstan’s GDP, with gold the biggest contributor. The country was one of the first to commit to increasing transparency in this sector, signing up to the EITI in 2004. Since then, Kyrgyzstan has worked with EITI to make significant progress towards greater transparency, and in 2018 passed a new Subsoil Law that requires beneficial ownership information for applicants and mining license holders. According to EITI, there are only two other countries - UK and Ukraine - that disclose beneficial ownership through open and accessible registers. By participating in the OpenOwnership pilot program, Kyrgyzstan will become pioneers in providing EITI beneficial ownership as open data in a form that can be linked globally, based on OpenOwnership’s data standard. Through this work, OpenOwnership will identify learnings that can apply across other EITI countries working to meet beneficial ownership commitments, and integrate these into our implementation guidance for governments. Thank you to our partners at the EITI International Secretariat and the Kyrgyzstan EITI Secretariat for their work so far towards making this partnership possible. We look forward to continuing our work with EITI and working with the Kyrgyzstan State Committee and technical implementers over the coming months. To learn more about the OpenOwnership pilot program and the benefits to your country or organization, contact Louise at louise@openownership.org.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New on the OpenOwnership Register - data from the Danish Business Register has been added</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/new-on-the-openownership-register-data-from-the-danish-business-register-has-been-added/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New on the OpenOwnership Register - data from the Danish Business Register has been added" /><published>2018-08-21T10:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T10:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/new-on-the-openownership-register-data-from-the-danish-business-register-has-been-added</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/new-on-the-openownership-register-data-from-the-danish-business-register-has-been-added/">&lt;p&gt;Denmark is the latest country to be added to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;OpenOwnership Register&lt;/a&gt;, the global platform that brings together beneficial ownership information from around the world. Data from the Danish Business Register on  about 300,000 companies can now be browsed and searched through our online portal. This addition also marks a significant milestone for us, taking the total count of companies represented in our database to over 5 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denmark is one of the few European countries that has already implemented a public register of beneficial ownership. It has gone one step further by making this information structured and available under an open license. &lt;a href=&quot;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32018L0843&quot;&gt;With new European anti-money laundering rules coming into force&lt;/a&gt;, public registers will be created across all member states. However, not all of them will be in open data format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this matter? At the moment, relationships that cross across jurisdictions are difficult to trace and understand. With every new data source added to the Register, more complicated transnational company ownership relationships become visible. For instance some companies in the United Kingdom report that they are owned by Danish companies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/danishdata.png&quot; alt=&quot;danishdata.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By linking the Danish data up, we can follow the trail of ownership one step further, to the individuals resident in Denmark who are the ultimate beneficial owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenOwnership aims to bring together data from many different countries - in Europe and beyond. This is necessary not only because we are doing more business internationally, but because many illegal activities that harm society - money laundering, tax evasion, fraud - also take place across borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing the number of countries and companies on the Register is core to &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/uploads/Open%20Ownership%20Mission%20Statement%202018.pdf&quot;&gt;our mission&lt;/a&gt; and we’re already lining up some more exciting pilot projects with countries looking to implement their own registers. As always, if you’d like to find out more you can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/get-involved/&quot;&gt;Sign up for email updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow us on Twitter - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenOwnership&quot;&gt;@openownership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting in touch with our team - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@openownership.org&quot;&gt;support@openownership.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Denmark is the latest country to be added to the OpenOwnership Register, the global platform that brings together beneficial ownership information from around the world. Data from the Danish Business Register on about 300,000 companies can now be browsed and searched through our online portal. This addition also marks a significant milestone for us, taking the total count of companies represented in our database to over 5 million.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving from policy to practice: reflections from Tblisi</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/moving-from-policy-to-practice-reflections-from-tblisi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving from policy to practice: reflections from Tblisi" /><published>2018-08-09T09:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-09T09:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/moving-from-policy-to-practice-reflections-from-tblisi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/moving-from-policy-to-practice-reflections-from-tblisi/">&lt;p&gt;Our team traveled to the Open Government Partnership’s Global Summit in Tbilisi with an important message to deliver: it’s time to make user needs the focus of beneficial ownership transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over two days in the run up to the Summit, we hosted representatives from eight countries, plus global civil society organisations at our workshop From policy to practice: Introducing the Beneficial Ownership Data Standard. Through hands-on exercises and group discussions, we explored the interactions between technology and policy in beneficial ownership implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our overarching message was that &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/not-just-public-but-useful-the-right-way-to-set-up-a-beneficial-ownership-register/&quot;&gt;policymakers need to think about user needs early and often in their implementations&lt;/a&gt;, because the intended benefits - crime detection and prevention, better markets - will be the result of the actions of users. We demonstrated how &lt;a href=&quot;http://standard.openownership.org&quot;&gt;the Beneficial Ownership Data Standard&lt;/a&gt;, which we at Open Data Services are developing in partnership with OpenOwnership, is a powerful tool for serving user needs, and cutting costs to implementers along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government representatives and policy experts also joined us for the launch of the Beneficial Ownership Transparency (BOT) Network, a peer learning network for implementers of beneficial ownership transparency that are interested in working along open data principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Exchanging ideas and best practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of these events we touched on issues of data validation, direct and indirect beneficial ownership, data protection and privacy, implementation of beneficial ownership registers, and data collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Standard provides a framework for collecting and publishing beneficial ownership data that integrates all of these issues, meaning that implementers don’t need to recreate the wheel. It also enables resulting data to be interoperable, more easily reused, and higher quality. It has been developed by dozens of experts in company data and standard-setting, with key use cases in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned about the policy and economic contexts that are shaping countries’ approaches to collecting beneficial ownership data, which challenge simplistic notions of beneficial ownership and test the scope of the Standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By guiding workshop participants through beneficial ownership research and data-mapping activities, we gave attendees a hands-on experience of the difference that well-structured data makes to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that participants left feeling better equipped to plan the policies and information systems needed for collecting and sharing good quality beneficial ownership data. And with the introduction of the BOT Network, government implementers now have a platform for sharing their experiences and learning from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you miss our events? Don’t fret! The slides are available in our resources section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/uploads/Introducing%20the%20beneficial%20ownership%20data%20standard%20-%20slides%20from%20the%20OGP%20Global%20Summit%202018.pdf&quot;&gt;Introducing the beneficial ownership data standard - slides from the OGP Global Summit 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/uploads/The%20Beneficial%20Ownership%20Transparency%20Network%20-%20slides%20from%20OGP%20Summit%202018.pdf&quot;&gt;The Beneficial Ownership Transparency Network - slides from OGP Summit 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome to make use of them in your own efforts to support beneficial ownership transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to hear more about our work, you can get involved by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/get-involved/&quot;&gt;Signing up for email updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Following us on Twitter - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenOwnership&quot;&gt;@openownership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Getting in touch with our team - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@openownership.org&quot;&gt;support@openownership.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our team traveled to the Open Government Partnership’s Global Summit in Tbilisi with an important message to deliver: it’s time to make user needs the focus of beneficial ownership transparency.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going beyond the Register - our Mission Statement</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/going-beyond-the-register-our-mission-statement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going beyond the Register - our Mission Statement" /><published>2018-08-01T16:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T16:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/going-beyond-the-register-our-mission-statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/going-beyond-the-register-our-mission-statement/">&lt;p&gt;Our founding organizations came together because of a shared vision: freely accessible, linked beneficial ownership information for the benefit of both business and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, we’ve talked to partners around the world - in civil society, business, and government. We’ve learned that there’s a lot more work to be done where the rubber meets the road. How do governments transform political commitment into implementation with genuine impact? How can civil society and business users take existing information and change the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re stepping up. Over the next two years, we’ll be focusing on practical interventions to change behaviours and standards so that publishing beneficial ownership data becomes the norm, not the exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still seems like yesterday to us, but almost fifteen months have passed since we launched the beta version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;world’s first global beneficial ownership register&lt;/a&gt;. Today, we’re delighted to celebrate a new landmark: OpenOwnership’s first Mission Statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as we expand our activity, our commitment remains the same - to drive greater corporate transparency across the world by making it easy to publish and access high-quality, linked data about who owns companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Mission Statement also articulates our vision, strategic priorities and the key goals we want to achieve by 2020 as we continue to grow our team, network, and (of course) the Register to meet the opportunities and challenges ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Mission Statement is available to read and download in our resources section &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/uploads/Open%20Ownership%20Mission%20Statement%202018.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to embark on this next phase of the OpenOwnership journey and look forward to continuing to work with our partners and stakeholders to realise our 2020 goals. If you would like to hear more about our work, you can get involved by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/get-involved/&quot;&gt;Signing up for email updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Following us on Twitter - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenOwnership&quot;&gt;@openownership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting in touch with our team - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@openownership.org&quot;&gt;support@openownership.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our founding organizations came together because of a shared vision: freely accessible, linked beneficial ownership information for the benefit of both business and society.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What we really mean when we talk about verification: Truth verification (part 4 of 4)</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-truth-verification-part-4-of-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What we really mean when we talk about verification: Truth verification (part 4 of 4)" /><published>2018-04-17T12:54:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T12:54:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-truth-verification-part-4-of-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-truth-verification-part-4-of-4/">&lt;p&gt;So far in this series on verification of beneficial ownership data, we have &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-part-1-of-4/&quot;&gt;given you an overview&lt;/a&gt; of what the term really means when applied to beneficial ownership, discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-authentication-and-authorization-part-2-of-4/&quot;&gt;how to tell if someone is who they say they are&lt;/a&gt; and whether they have the right to report beneficial ownership data, and explained the impact &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-validation-part-3-of-4/&quot;&gt;in-line validation&lt;/a&gt; of data has on data quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At every stage we have emphasised that there is no guarantee that any piece of beneficial ownership data gives a true picture of company ownership, but that making the information available as open data significantly increases the difficulties and risks for those who try to lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing authentication, authorization, and validation - and doing them well - is not about providing guarantees about the data, but about improving the data quality. This means distinguishing bad data from good, clarity from obfuscation, mistakes from lies, and holding people accountable for their statements. But ultimately criminals, money launderers, corrupt politicians, and others with bad intentions, will lie, and those lies are hard to catch out. In fact, it is close to impossible to know if any beneficial ownership statement is actually true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to understand why, it’s important to consider what has traditionally been offered as ‘proof’ of beneficial ownership to registrars, be they a corporate service provider (CSP) or Companies House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shareholder certificates, declarations of trust, and other documents that may be considered ‘proof’ of beneficial ownership are all essentially the same thing: statements about who the beneficial owner of a company or trust is at a point in time. And more than that, they are proofs produced by the very people making the statements (remember, many share certificates these days are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jonathanlea.net/2013/free-share-certificate-template/&quot;&gt;printed-out Word documents&lt;/a&gt;, and shareholder registers are often Excel spreadsheets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, they are no more guaranteed to contain the truth than a similar statement made to a centrally-held register. Whether these documents are notarized and certified to contain the truth do not make them any more true. This is not materially different from certifying to a company registrar that the information you are reporting to them is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to truth verification, one of its fundamental principles is that, in order to verify that a fact is true, it needs to be expressed in at least two different ways. This is not dissimilar to the new best practice of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/landing/2step/&quot;&gt;two-step verification&lt;/a&gt; for internet accounts (e.g. email). This requires you to verify who you are both through something you know (a password), and something you have (a phone), making it harder for anyone else to access your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, beneficial ownership is effectively a statement about the material conditions of a company at a point in time. There is no second way to express it, particularly in cases where someone is attempting to hide their identity. No physical asset exists that can serve as proof you own a company. Even with the rise of digital identities and blockchain-like registers, it’s still very difficult to prove that the person is not a nominee, or that no secret side agreement exists giving control or benefit to someone else. The closest we can get is identifying financial activity (e.g. transfers between bank accounts) that links back to the subject being investigated. However, this avenue is only really open to law enforcement agencies - this information isn’t available as a means of verification to the bodies that administer and collate company registers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our partners at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalwitness.org/&quot;&gt;Global Witness&lt;/a&gt; know first hand what it takes to uncover the true owners of a company or resource when they are determined to hide. To take just one example, their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=728&amp;amp;v=_1RRNggnM6A&quot;&gt;2013 investigation&lt;/a&gt; into land sales in Sarawak, Malaysia showed how the country’s company ownership laws could be circumvented using offshoring to allow foreign ‘investors’, lawyers and public officials to make huge profits on land gifted by the state. Uncovering the truth required the Global Witness team to pose as investors and take hidden cameras into secret meetings to obtain evidence that would never show up in a paper trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is because of the resource-intensive nature of these investigations that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalwitness.org/en/press-releases/new-global-register-shine-light-anonymous-companies-root-cause-corrupt-illegal-activities/&quot;&gt;civil society has called most vocally&lt;/a&gt; for public, open data on beneficial ownership. Because although no one can guarantee the truth of what’s reported to a register, this data provides crucial leads and red flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of companies are above-board businesses that operate ethically. Only a small percentage of corporate vehicles are being abused for criminal or unethical purposes, which their beneficial owners will naturally want to hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-part-1-of-4/&quot;&gt;Here we come full circle&lt;/a&gt; to the development of indicators for when beneficial ownership data contains clues that someone is hiding. Every user group, from law enforcement to the private sector, is likely to have their own set of due diligence and red flagging procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example of a red flag is that a company is deliberately suppressing information on who controls it. Early research from Global Witness shows that many companies in the UK register are doing this. For example, 7,000 companies list a company incorporated in a tax haven as their beneficial owner and hundreds of companies are using circular ownership structures, meaning we have no way of knowing which individuals actually control these companies. Global Witness is developing a system that uses red flags to automatically pick out suspect companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember that collecting beneficial ownership data is not an end in itself - it must be designed from the ground up to meet the needs of users. The datasets we produce must lend themselves to the development of red flags, and to reducing the number of loopholes and ambiguities that enable individuals to evade accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly why we’re developing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;beneficial ownership data standard&lt;/a&gt; that has been informed by research into the use cases for beneficial ownership data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have enjoyed this series and would like to hear more about our work, you can get involved by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/get-involved/&quot;&gt;Signing up for email updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Following us on Twitter - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OpenOwnership&quot;&gt;@openownership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting in touch with our team - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@openownership.org&quot;&gt;info@openownership.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So far in this series on verification of beneficial ownership data, we have given you an overview of what the term really means when applied to beneficial ownership, discussed how to tell if someone is who they say they are and whether they have the right to report beneficial ownership data, and explained the impact in-line validation of data has on data quality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beneficial ownership transparency in Ukraine: what’s next?</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/beneficial-ownership-transparency-in-ukraine-whats-next/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beneficial ownership transparency in Ukraine: what’s next?" /><published>2018-04-04T13:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-04T13:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/beneficial-ownership-transparency-in-ukraine-whats-next</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/beneficial-ownership-transparency-in-ukraine-whats-next/">&lt;p&gt;In 2016 Ukraine became the second country in the world (after the UK) to implement a public register of the beneficial owners of corporate entities registered in country. It subsequently became the first country in the world to &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/ukraine-becomes-the-first-country-to-integrate-with-openownership/&quot;&gt;commit to integrating this data with the OpenOwnership Register&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the first step toward integration, the OpenOwnership team undertook a holistic review of Ukraine’s current beneficial ownership regime. Working closely with Ministry of Justice officials and users in civil society and government, we assessed the impact of existing technical, business process, and policy frameworks on the quality and usability of Ukraine’s beneficial ownership data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are pleased to publish our findings in full. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/uploads/Improving%20beneficial%20ownership%20transparency%20in%20Ukraine.pdf&quot;&gt;Improving beneficial ownership transparency in Ukraine: Review and recommendations&lt;/a&gt; we assess the progress made so far and provide recommendations for strengthening Ukraine’s beneficial ownership regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our assessment begins with the assumption that data usage determines whether the policy goals of stemming corruption and improving Ukraine’s business environment will be met. Overall, Ukraine has taken several important steps to make its beneficial ownership data accessible to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since June 2017, the Ukrainian Ministry of Justice has made beneficial ownership data available as an open data set for bulk download (along with other company data). To date, approximately 253,000 Ukrainian companies have reported their beneficial ownership to the companies register.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a leadership level there is a clear understanding of the benefits of beneficial ownership transparency across the private, public and third sectors. However, there is room for improvements that will make the realization of these benefits more likely. We identified a number of key areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level of compliance:&lt;/strong&gt; The current low level of compliance (less than 20% of all Ukrainian companies are accounted for) demonstrates the need for a stronger system of sanctions and robust enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data quality:&lt;/strong&gt; There are currently a number of limitations that lower the quality and usability of the data collected. These include a lack of beneficial ownership data in machine-readable format, unreliable systems of disambiguation for individuals and companies, a lack of granularity in the data (in particular on the means of control), and no representation of chains of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance of records:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently, no information is given on when the data was submitted, and no confirmation statement is required. This makes it impossible to assess the timeliness of the data being submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation:&lt;/strong&gt; There is a clear need to close possible loopholes by requiring the reporting of detailed beneficial ownership data, including by using the definition of “beneficial owner” contained in the law as a basis for creating a clear test of beneficial ownership to share as guidance. The lack of in-line validation of beneficial ownership data at the point of collection, and inefficient processes of verification thereafter,&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have made a range of policy and technical recommendations to the Ministry of Justice, which are set out in full in the report. Our top line recommendations to the Ministry include taking action to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;urgently address the problem of low compliance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update regulations to require comprehensive data on beneficial owners and the disclosure of means of control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remove the high 25% threshold of shareholding that beneficial owners must exceed in order for the reporting requirement to kick in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create forms to collect beneficial ownership as structured data by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ensure that there are reliable means to disambiguate individuals and companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Ministry of Justice needs to work with technical implementers to design inline validation and business rules into new forms for collecting data and processes for comparing it with other relevant datasets in order to verify its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the steps Ukraine has already taken put it ahead of countries that have not yet transformed their commitments to beneficial ownership transparency into implementation. By implementing these recommendations and working to meet the highest standard on beneficial ownership transparency, Ukraine will continue to demonstrate its leadership in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to be part of this journey. We look forward to our continued work with our Ukrainian colleagues to achieve the ultimate goals of greater beneficial transparency: the reduction of corruption and strengthening of the business environment and good corporate governance in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full report can be downloaded from our resources section: &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/resources/&quot;&gt;https://openownership.org/resources/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In 2016 Ukraine became the second country in the world (after the UK) to implement a public register of the beneficial owners of corporate entities registered in country. It subsequently became the first country in the world to commit to integrating this data with the OpenOwnership Register.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What we really mean when we talk about verification: Validation (part 3 of 4)</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-validation-part-3-of-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What we really mean when we talk about verification: Validation (part 3 of 4)" /><published>2018-03-01T07:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-01T07:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-validation-part-3-of-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-validation-part-3-of-4/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third instalment of our four-part blog post series on verification. To recap, in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-part-1-of-4/&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt;, we broke down the term “verification” into three distinct steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensuring that the person making a statement about beneficial ownership is who they say they are, and that they have the right to make the claim (authentication and authorization);&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensuring that the data submitted is a legitimate possible value (validation);&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Verifying that the statement made is actually true (which we will call truth verification).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/what-we-really-mean-when-we-talk-about-verification-authentication-and-authorization-part-2-of-4/&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed authentication and authorization. In this post, we will discuss the process of validation and why it’s important for generating high-quality beneficial ownership data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validation ensures that data being reported on forms consists of a legitimate possible values – AAA12 344 is not a valid UK postal code, for example, nor is 1990-12-40 a valid date. Such validation is much more effective, more reliable and less burdensome for all when users enter their data on on electronic forms that simply do not allow data to be entered unless it follows clear validation rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalwitness.org/en/blog/what-does-uk-beneficial-ownership-data-show-us/&quot;&gt;a dive into the UK’s beneficial ownership data&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalwitness.org/en/&quot;&gt;Global Witness&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datakind.org/&quot;&gt;DataKind&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://opencorporates.com/&quot;&gt;OpenCorporates&lt;/a&gt; highlight a number of areas where validation could significantly improve data quality. People with British nationality indicated this in over 500 different ways (see the word cloud below to get an idea of the variations). There were also over 2,000 beneficial owners who reported being born in 2016, which is stretching the definition of ‘young entrepreneur’!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/wordcloud.png&quot; alt=&quot;wordcloud.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more room a system leaves for ambiguities, the more it creates loopholes that allow individuals to hide their identities and escape detection. The risk is heightened when you factor in the global nature of money laundering, and the challenge of collecting beneficial ownership data that is meaningful across jurisdictions. Date of birth is currently the best tool for disambiguating between individuals with similar names who are operating cross-jurisdictionally, as national ID numbers are only meaningful in the jurisdiction of origin. This is why validating the date of birth is so critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These issues could be solved easily by forcing data submitters to choose from an enumerated list of allowed values (for example a drop-down menu of nationalities), and by ensuring that the year of birth entered is in the past, and that possible entries are limited according to the minimum legal age for a company owner (16 in the UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t difficult to do. The OpenOwnership &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;Register&lt;/a&gt; has had date and nationality validation built in since the very beginning. Should a user attempt to enter an unlikely date of birth, they receive an error that does not allow them to proceed until it’s corrected. Our partners at Global Witness tell us that Companies House has recently made similar changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A related issue is that of addresses. To a money laundering investigator in civil society or law enforcement, an address is a critical piece of information that can show a connection between companies that otherwise seem unrelated. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transparency.org.uk/publications/offshore-in-the-uk/#.Woa_QYLLf-Y&quot;&gt;Transparency International UK’s analysis of Scottish Limited Partnerships&lt;/a&gt;, a type of corporate entity initially exempt from the obligation to report beneficial ownership, found that a majority of SLPs were registered to just 10 addresses. Although sharing an address doesn’t necessarily indicate any linkage (some addresses of corporate service providers in Delaware have tens of thousands of entities registered at them), it can surface patterns, which together with other data points can provide valuable leads for investigators,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validating an address is more difficult than, say, a date of birth, but it can be done in most countries (as ecommerce sites do every day). It is also possible (though rare) to validate that the addresses actually exist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.companiesoffice.govt.nz/companies/app/ui/pages/companies/6127531/addresses&quot;&gt;as the New Zealand company register does&lt;/a&gt;. Similarly, enforcing some validation on company names and company numbers can make it more difficult to hide corporate networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, validation doesn’t make it impossible for people to report incorrect information. But it has a major impact on data quality by limiting the possibility of mistakes. And it does at least make it impossible for individuals to conceal their identities by entering values that are unlikely. That reduces the “noise” of unintentional bad data, making the intentional errors easier to spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not clear that company service providers offer any meaningful validation when they collect data on those who set up and benefit from companies, including the beneficial owners. In countries that are establishing central registers of beneficial ownership, the primary difficulty is the medium through which data is submitted. Company registrars in countries with low levels of internet connectivity typically receive data on a paper form that is then entered into an electronic system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even assuming there’s some validation at the point of data entry, this system is prone to generate errors because data submitters are not entering data themselves. Data quality would be significantly improved if company registrars took steps to facilitate the usage of electronic tools by data submitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both validation and authentication/authorization may make it more difficult for corrupt individuals to lie, and generally improve data quality, but they do not make it impossible. In our next and final post, we return to the crux of the issue of verification: is there a way to tell whether beneficial ownership data that has been reported is true?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll check back here in a couple of weeks for the last instalment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="verification" /><summary type="html">Welcome to the third instalment of our four-part blog post series on verification. To recap, in our first post, we broke down the term “verification” into three distinct steps:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ukrainian beneficial ownership data now available</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/ukrainian-beneficial-ownership-data-now-available/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ukrainian beneficial ownership data now available" /><published>2018-01-03T15:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T15:27:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/ukrainian-beneficial-ownership-data-now-available</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/ukrainian-beneficial-ownership-data-now-available/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://register.openownership.org/&quot;&gt;OpenOwnership Register&lt;/a&gt; has been updated to include information about the beneficial owners of over 240,000 Ukrainian companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information is collected in Ukraine’s Unified States Register and was recently released as an open data set. OpenOwnership has gone one step further, however, to parse the original unstructured data into a structured format, and partially transliterate the records from Cyrillic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can search for Ukrainian companies on the OpenOwnership platform and will be able to download the full dataset from the Register home page in the future. Ukrainian users who are interested in receiving a download of the structured data in the original Cyrillic can contact info@openownership.org to request this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Ukraine became &lt;a href=&quot;https://openownership.org/news/ukraine-becomes-the-first-country-to-integrate-with-openownership/&quot;&gt;the first country to sign on to integrate with OpenOwnership&lt;/a&gt;. As part of this program, we will work with Ukrainian authorities to improve the quality and completeness of the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The OpenOwnership Register has been updated to include information about the beneficial owners of over 240,000 Ukrainian companies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Call: Governance consultant</title><link href="https://www.openownership.org/news/open-call-governance-consultant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Call: Governance consultant" /><published>2017-12-11T09:08:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T09:08:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.openownership.org/news/open-call-governance-consultant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.openownership.org/news/open-call-governance-consultant/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenOwnership&lt;/strong&gt; seeks a governance consultant to work with the Steering Group and staff to help us formalise and adopt an efficient and effective governance structure as we move into the second phase of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assignment:&lt;/strong&gt; Governance consultant to provide recommendations on governance structure to OpenOwnership Steering Group&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration:&lt;/strong&gt; Approximately 5-10 days work&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Remote&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; Bids welcome in the range of £5000 to £8,000&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting date:&lt;/strong&gt; ASAP&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; December 22, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt;  Email a CV, example of previous work, and cover letter detailing how you would proceed with the assignment and including a quote to info@openownership.org with “Governance consultant” in the subject line.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;About OpenOwnership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenOwnership is the initiative of a group of leading organizations advocating for greater financial transparency and an end to anonymous company ownership and control structures. We do this by providing technology and technical assistance that supports both publishers and users of beneficial ownership data. Through our partners and independently, we aim to lead the creation of an open data and policy ecosystem that ends the abuse of anonymously owned companies by money launderers, corrupt politicians and businesses, and tax evaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2017 we launched the OpenOwnership register, the first global public beneficial ownership register in the world. The OpenOwnership register and data standard should enable businesses to know who they are doing business with, financial institutions to know who their customers are, citizens to see who wins public contracts, and law enforcement to hold individuals accountable for crime and corruption. We are developing an associated data standard and have committed partnerships from governments and companies to the next phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The next phase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has completed its first phase; we have a minimal viable product, private sector, public sector and civil society stakeholder working groups, growing visibility of the tool’s potential via strategic communications and external relationships, commitments from two governments to partner on data exchange and a strategy for the coming years to generate impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phase 2 will scale up the project to implementation and impact phase and so, will require the development of internal policies and procedures that can professionalise the project to realise its potential and ensure its sustainability. For that to happen we need to establish an effective and efficient governance structure and policies and procedures that ensures we capitalise on opportunities and current funding realities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Current set-up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The register has been established by a coalition of international organizations, including Global Witness, Open Contracting Partnership, OpenCorporates, The B Team, The Web Foundation, Transparency International and ONE. These organisations compose the Steering Group, co-chaired by the representatives from two organisations. The Steering group hired a coordinator to facilitate the Steering Group organizations’ partnership and delivery of the project plan for the first year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OO staff base will now grow from a single coordinator to a small team charged with delivery of the strategy and managed by a Project Lead. Overall governance, ownership and responsibility for the project remains with the Steering Group and they sign off on the strategy and approve any major organisational developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September, Fund for the City of New York became the fiscal sponsor of OpenOwnership. OO staff are employed by that partner and are responsible for delivery of activities and financial management of the project. FCNY provides light-touch technical oversight of funds and legal governance, but the Steering Group remains responsible, for the direction, the strategy, and as the ultimate ‘owners’ of the project. We are now seeking to formalise and adopt an efficient and effective governance structure to enable strategic long-term governance of the project and ensure the buy-in and input of OpenOwnership stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Terms of Reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect and analyse input from key stakeholders about the governance needs of OpenOwnership.
Based on consultation, research, and experience propose options with recommendations for overall governance structure, oversight and authority including  recommendations for Steering Group membership, composition, roles and working methods (including decision-making, sign off of key policies and strategies and transparency).
Present options to the Steering Committee for discussion.
Develop final outline of the option chosen.
Support processes to share final decisions with OpenOwnership stakeholders including potentially hosting workshop to share conclusions (online or in person) if relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Outputs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Options paper with recommendations on governance&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Final outline of governance option chosen&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OpenOwnership does not discriminate in its selection and employment practices. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, colour, religion, sex, national origin, political affiliation, sexual orientation, gender identity, marital status, disability, protected veteran status, genetic information, age, or other legally protected characteristics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OpenOwnership seeks a governance consultant to work with the Steering Group and staff to help us formalise and adopt an efficient and effective governance structure as we move into the second phase of the project.</summary></entry></feed>